Guide to the Milbank Memorial Fund Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Biographical and Historical Records, 1898 -1973; Series II; 3 linear feet (6 boxes)
  - Historical Records
    - Memorial Choir, Princeton University Chapel: miscellaneous prints and related material, 1928, 1931, undated (Box 28, Folder 64)
    - Memorial Choir, Princeton University Chapel: photographs, 1928 (Box 28, Folder 65-66)
    - Twenty-fifth anniversary
      - Historical data, 1930 January (Box 28, Folder 67)
      - Dinner addresses, 1930 April 3 (Box 28, Folder 68)
      - Historical sketch, "The Living Hand, Elizabeth Milbank Anderson", 1930 April 3 (Box 28, Folder 69)
      - Historical sketch, "Twenty-five Years of Philanthropy", 1930 November (Box 28, Folder 70)
      - "Historical Sketch of the Milbank Memorial Fund, 1905-1929", 1930 (Box 28, Folder 71)
    - Memoranda re: program development, 1931 November-December (Box 28, Folder 72)
    - Memoranda re: program of activities, 1931-1934 (Box 28, Folder 73)
    - Memorandum re: fund's operations, including historical summary, personnel and financial data, 1932 June 21 (Box 29, Folder 74)
    - Minutes of Board of Directors, special meeting re: account of the trustees settlement, 1933 June 20 (Box 29, Folder 75)
    - Newsletters and record of distribution for News Digest, 1934-1940 (Box 29, Folder 76)
    - Correspondence and report re: "A Survey of the Operations of the Fund Based Upon a Study of Its Finance, 1935.", 1935 February-June (Box 29, Folder 77)
    - Certificate of Incorporation and Bylaws (as Amended to March 20, 1942), 1942 March 20 (Box 29, Folder 78)
    - Progress reports, 1942-1950 (Box 29, Folder 79)
    - Minutes of Board of Directors re: fund's history and future history, 1949 October 21 (Box 29, Folder 80)
    - Progress reports, 1951-1960 (Box 29, Folder 81-82)
    - Correspondence and historical sketch re: Greenwich (Connecticut) Library, 1957-1969 (Box 29, Folder 83)
    - Memoranda re: Milbank Memorial Fund Quarterly, 1960 August (Box 29, Folder 84)
    - Progress reports, 1961-1962 (Box 29, Folder 85)
    - Summary of fund's work in population, 1969 (Box 29, Folder 86)
    - Proposed program, 1971 October 19 (Box 29, Folder 87)
    - Summary statement of program, 1972 (Box 29, Folder 88)
    - "History of the Borden Company", 1973, undated (Box 29, Folder 89)
- Bellevue-Yorkville Project Records, 1922-1934; Series III; 1 linear foot (2 boxes)
  BELLEVUE-YORKVILLE PROJECT RECORDS is arranged chronologically.
  - Vital statistics report, 1922-1924, 1922-1931 (Box 30, Folder 1-2)
  - Annual reports, 1927-1928 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Special study reports, 1927-1929, 1927-1931 (Box 30, Folder 4-5)
  - Bellevue-Yorkville Health News, 1929-1930 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Annual reports and reprints, 1930-1932 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Bellevue-Yorkville Health News, 1931-1933 (Box 31, Folder 8-9)
  - Report, Cervico-Vaginitis of Gonococcal Origin in Children, 1933 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Reprint, "An Organized Community Health Program," Milbank Memorial Quarterly, 1934 October (Box 31, Folder 11)
- Oversize, Series IV
  - United States Congress, House Select Committee on Small Business: tabulations charts showing income and expenditure, 1905-1963 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Historical records, twenty-fifth anniversary: charts and tables, "Twenty-five Years of Philanthropy", 1930 November (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - United States Congress, House Select Committee on Small Business (W. Patman): financial reports and statements of securities, 1951-1959 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - United States Congress, House Special Committee to Investigate Tax Exempt Foundations and Comparable Organizations: financial charts re: report for committee, 1952 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Biographical records: photographs, undated (Box 32, Folder 5)
- Additional material, Accession 1985-M-029
  - Milbank Memorial Fund Commission for the Study of Higher Education for Public Health
    - Correspondence, 1960-1983 (Box 1–2)
    - Personnel, 1960-1983 (Box 3–4)
    - Meetings, 1960-1983 (Box 5–7)
    - Public Health Schools, 1960-1983 (Box 8–9)
    - Organizations, 1960-1983 (Box 10–11)
    - Final reports, 1960-1983 (Box 12–18)
- Additional material, Accession 1985-M-045
  - 1970s
    - A - H (Box 1)
    - I - M (Box 2)
    - N - W (Box 3)
  - Board of Directors Meetings
    - 1968 - 1974 March (Box 4)
    - 1974 May - 1978 (Box 5)
  - Burney, Leroy
    - Speeches, 1959-1961
    - Miscellaneous papers, undated (Box 6)
- Additional material, 1964-1985; Accession 1991-M-006; 6 linear feet (6 boxes)
  Addition inventory by Carol King 1990 Aug
  Received from: Milbank Memorial Fund, 1990 Jul 23
  - African Medical Education Program (A.M.E.P.)
    - Administrative and general correspondence, 1970-1977 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous appeals, A-L, 1970-1978 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous appeals, M-Z, 1970-1978 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous appeals, general correspondence, 1970-1979 (Box 1)
    - University of Dar Es Salaam, Faculty of Medicine finances, 1970-1977 (Box 1)
    - University of Dar Es Salaam, Faculty of Medicine, Division Social and Community Medicine, 1976-1984 (Box 1)
    - Present grantees (16 folders listed by personal name) of University of Dar Es Salaam, 1968-1978 (Box 1–2)
    - Former grantees (24 folders listed by personal name) of University of Dar Es Salaam (Box 2)
    - Calendar of the University of Dar Es Salaam, 1977-1978 (Box 2)
    - African Medical and Research Foundation (AMREF), Second Annual Progress Report, 1979 (Box 3)
    - Schedule of visits to London Geneva, East Africa, 1971-1974 (Box 3)
    - Visit to East Africa by Dr. L. E. Burney and J. S. Baugh to review the Fund's East African program and interview grantees and appellants, 1974 January 15 February 5 (Box 3)
    - Visit to London, Nottingham, Geneva, Nairobi, and Dar Es Salaam to review the Fund's A.M.E.P., 1974 January 15-February 5 (Box 3)
    - Schedule of visits to England and East Africa, 1976 (Box 3)
    - Nairobi visit, 1976 (Box 3)
    - England, Makerere University, Christopher H. Wood, visit file, 1976 (Box 3)
    - Dar Es Salaam visit, 1976 (Box 3)
    - East Africa visit, 1976-1978 (Box 3)
    - University of Nairobi, Faculty of Medicine, Dept. of Community Health, 1976-1979 (Box 3)
    - "Development and Evaluation of Self-Instructional Materials in Epidemiology for Medical and Para-Medical Students in East Africa," University of Dar Es Salaam, 1977-1978 (Box 3)
    - Annual report of University of Nairobi, 1976 October-1977 October (Box 3)
    - Sundry reports, 1970-1979 (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous papers and reports on programs in Africa, 1969-1976 (Box 3)
    - Grantees (33 folders listed by personal name) of University of Nairobi, Makerere University, University of Ghana Medical School, 1970-1979 (Box 4)
    - List of medical journals for grantees in East Africa, 1978 (Box 5)
    - University of Nairobi, Faculty of Medicine, Dept. of Community Health, 1976-1983 (Box 5)
  - Medical Services International, Inc.
    - Annual Reports for Foreign and Domestic Corporations, 1969-1977 (Box 5)
    - Description and bylaws, 1967 (Box 5)
    - Annual board meeting, 1977 September (Box 5)
    - Appeals, 1965-1967 (Box 5)
    - Development grants, 1969-1977 (Box 5)
    - Short form 990 annual reports, 1970-1976 (Box 5)
    - U.S. Trust Company of New York, 1970-1978 (Box 5)
    - Milbank, Tweed, Hadley & McCloy, 1971-1978 (Box 5)
    - Minutes of meetings, 1964-1978 (Box 5)
  - Milbank Memorial Fund
    - Technical board minutes, 1961-1985 May 21 (Box 6)
    - Summaries of appeals, 1980-1981 (Box 6)
- Additional material, 1976-1990; Accession 1991-M-099; 10.75 linear feet (9 boxes)
  Materials in Accession 1991-M-099 are restricted until 2021. Written permission from the President of the Milbank Memorial Fund is required for access.
  Addition inventory by Carol King 1991 Jun
  Received from: Milbank Memorial Fund, 1991 Jun 27
  The manuscript files consist of correspondence and memoranda of editor David P. Willis and his editorial staff with authors and reviewers of submitted manuscripts and publishers and distributors of accepted articles. Manuscript reviews, review procedures, and copyright transfers by authors to the Milbank memorial Fund are included in the records.
  - Milbank Memorial Fund Quarterly/Health and Society and the Milbank Quarterly manuscript files
    - #001 - #201 (Box 1)
    - #202 - #337 (Box 2)
    - #338 - #500 (Box 3)
    - #500A - #641 (Box 4)
    - #642 - #750 (Box 5)
    - #751 - #854A (Box 6)
    - #855 - #944 (Box 7)
    - #945 - #1019 (Box 8)
    - #1020 - #1107 (Box 9)
- Additional material, 1920-1984; Accession 1992-M-060; 6.25 linear feet (7 boxes)
  Addition inventory by Diane E. Kaplan 1992 April
  Received from: Milbank Memorial Fund, 1992 March 9
  Box 4 in Accession 1992-M-060 contains employee records which are restricted for seventy-five years after the employee's termination date.
  - M.Q.
    - Publications - Contract with George G. Reader, M.D/Department of Public Health of Cornell University (Box 1)
    - Publications - Agreement - Dartmouth Printing Co. (Box 1)
    - Publications - Payment to Cornell University/Editorial Services Agreement (Box 1)
    - Publications - MMF Quarterly/Health & Society /Application for Second Class Mail Privileges (Box 1)
    - Publications - Checks received from Prodist - January 1, 1975 - January 28, 1980 (Box 1)
    - Publications - Prodist - Inventory Reports January 1, 1975 - March 28, 1979 (Box 1)
    - Round-Table Conference - December 1977/Grant from National Center for Health Services Research (Box 1)
    - Publications - Prodist - Samples of Forms (Box 1)
    - Publications - Dartmouth Medical School - Accounts (Box 1)
    - Distribution Lists of Dr. Clyde Kiser's Book/"The Milbank Memorial Fund-It's Leaders and It's work, 1905-1974" (Box 1)
    - Distribution Lists: (Box 1)
      - Gratis List (Box 1)
      - Subscriptions by individuals (Box 1)
      - Subscriptions by institutions (Box 1)
      - MMF Health & Society - volume 55, 1977 - List of unpaid accounts (Box 1)
      - Cancelled Subscriptions - 1978 Subscribers (Box 1)
    - Gratis Invoices (Box 1)
    - Recipients of Dr. Kiser's Book (Box 1)
    - Milbank Memorial Fund - Publications Program - Financial, Economic, and Business Aspects (Box 2)
    - Publications - New Agreement - Neale Watson Academic Publications, Inc. - 1978 (Box 2)
    - Publications - Letter of Intent - Neale Watson Academic Publications & MMF - 1974 (Box 2)
    - Publications - Letter of Intent - Neale Watson Academic Publications & MMF - 1972/1973 (Box 2)
  - Chapel Hill Office
    - Sheps, M.D., Cecil G.
      - Continuing Chairman of the Commission, January 1, 1976 - December 31, 1976 (Box 2)
    - Setting Up Office - Chapel Hill Office Procedures (Box 2)
    - Lease Agreement and Rent Receipts (Box 2)
    - Legal Matters (Box 2)
    - North Carolina National Bank, Chapel Hill (MMF Commission for the Study of Higher Education for Public Health) - 1972 (Box 2)
    - Administrative Matters - General May 1972 - June 1973 (Box 2)
    - North Carolina - Return of Organization Exempt from Income Tax (Box 2)
    - Milbank Memorial Fund Commission for the Study of Higher/Education for Public Health - 1973 - General Correspondence (Box 2)
    - Study of Higher Education in Public Health - General Correspondence (Box 2)
    - Sheps, Cecil G., M.D. - 1976 - (Box 2)
  - President's and Treasurer's Reports
    - MMF Reports - President's - 1972 - 1983 (Box 3)
  - Financial Statements - Auditor's Reports
    - MMF - Reports - Auditors - 1920 - 1922 (Box 3)
    - MMF - Reports - Auditors - 1923 - 1925 (Box 3)
    - MMF - Reports - Auditors - 1926 - 1928 (Box 3)
    - MMF - Reports - Auditors - 1929 - 1931 (Box 3)
    - MMF - Reports - Auditors - 1932 - 1934 (Box 3)
    - MMF - Reports - Auditors - 1935 - 1937 (Box 3)
    - MMF - Reports - Auditors - 1938 - 1940 (Box 3)
    - MMF - Reports - Auditors - 1941 - 1943 (Box 3)
    - MMF - Reports - Auditors - 1944 - 1946 (Box 3)
    - MMF - Reports - Auditors - 1947 - 1949 (Box 3)
    - MMF - Reports - Auditors - 1950 - 1952 (Box 3)
    - MMF - Reports - Auditors - 1953 - 1955 (Box 3)
    - MMF - Reports - Auditors - 1956 - 1958 (Box 3)
    - MMF - Reports - Auditors - 1959 - 1961 (Box 3)
    - MMF - Reports - Auditors - 1962 - 1964 (Box 3)
    - MMF - Reports - Auditors - 1965 - 1967 (Box 3)
    - MMF - Reports - Auditors - 1968 - 1970 (Box 3)
    - MMF - Reports - Auditors - 1971 - 1973 (Box 3)
    - MMF - Reports - Auditors - 1974 - 1976 (Box 3)
    - MMF - Reports - Auditors - 1977 - 1976 (Box 3)
    - MMF - Reports - Auditors - 1978 - 1977 (Box 3)
    - MMF - Reports - Auditors - 1979 - 1978 (Box 3)
    - MMF - Reports - Auditors - 1980 - 1979 (Box 3)
    - MMF - Reports - Auditors - 1981 - 1980 (Box 3)
    - MMF - Reports - Auditors - 1982 - 1981 (Box 3)
    - MMF - Reports - Auditors - 1983 - 1982 (Box 3)
    - MMF - Reports - Auditors - 1984 - 1983 (Box 3)
  - Technical Board and Other Consultants
    - Honoria - Budgets - Technical Board and Consultants, 1969-1982 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      Materials are restricted until January 1, 2057.
    - Backett, E. Maurice, M.B., 1967 October 10-1971 April 30 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      Materials are restricted until January 1, 2046.
    - Baehr, George, M.D. - Consultant, 1946-1978 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      Died September 6, 1978.
      Materials are restricted untul January 1, 2053.
    - Bellin, M.D., Lowell E. - Tech. Bd. (Could not accept appointment), 1975 June 1 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      Materials restricted until January 1, 2050.
    - Burns, Eveline M., Ph.D., 1971 August-1973 May (Box 4, Folder 5)
      Materials restricted until January 1, 2048.
    - Cooper, Theodore, M.D. - Tech. Bd., 1979 September 1-1982 May 31 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      Materials restricted until January 1, 2057.
    - Densen, Paul M., D.Sc. - Tech. Bd., 1965 October 12-1970 April 30 (Box 4, Folder 7)
      Materials restricted until January 1, 2045.
    - Deuschle, Kurt W., M.D. - Tech. Bd., 1969 May-1974 May (Box 4, Folder 8)
      Materials restricted until January 1, 2049.
    - Gruenberg, Ernest M., M.D. - Tech. Bd., 1977 June-1982 May 31 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Gruenberg, Ernest, M.D. - Consultant, 1961 October 1-1967 (Box 4, Folder 10)
      Materials restricted until January 1, 2042.
    - Haughton, James G., M.D., 1971 May-1972 June 30 (Box 4, Folder 11)
      Materials restricted until January 1, 2047.
    - Hilleboe, Herman E., M.D., 1963-1974 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Horwitz, Abraham, M.D., 1963 May 1-1975 May 31 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Jackson, Arva, M.S.W. - Tech. Bd., 1973 June 1-1975 May 31 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - King, C. Glen, Ph.D. (Tech. Bd. and BOD) Died January 24, 1988, 1963 May 1-1972 May (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Levin, Lowell S., Ed.D., 1965-1974 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - McIntosh, Rustin, M.D., 1956 December 19-1976 May 31 (Box 4, Folder 17)
      Materials restricted until January 1, 2051.
    - Newman, Howard N., M.B.A., J.D. - Tech. Bd., 1974 June-1977 May (Box 4A, Folder 1)
      Materials are restricted until January 1, 2052.
    - Payne, Anthony M.M., M.D. - Consultant, 1965 May 13-1970 April 30 (Box 4A, Folder 2)
      Materials are restricted until January 1, 2045
    - Perrin, Edward B., Ph.D. - Tech. Bd., 1974 June 1-1976 May 31 (Box 4A, Folder 3)
      Materials are restricted until January 1, 2051.
    - Piore, Nora K. - Tech. Bd., 1977 January 1-1978 May 31 (Box 4A, Folder 4)
    - Rice, Dorothy P. - Tech. Bd., 1975 June 1-1982 May 31 (Box 4A, Folder 5)
    - Sanazaro, Paul J., M.D., 1971 May-1972 May (Box 4A, Folder 6)
    - Saward, Ernest W., M.D., 1971 August-1978 May (Box 4A, Folder 7)
    - Shanholtz, Mack Irwin, M.D. - Tech. Bd., 1973 June 1-1975 May 31 (Box 4A, Folder 8)
    - Schorr, Alvin L., M.S.W., 1971 May-1977 May (Box 4A, Folder 9)
    - Sigmond, Robert M. - Tech. Bd., 1973 June 1-1976 May 31 (Box 4A, Folder 10)
    - Silver, George A., M.D., 1963 May 1-1975 May 31 (Box 4A, Folder 11)
    - Snipe, James - Visiting Consultant, 1971 September 16-October 31 (Box 4A, Folder 12)
    - Somers, Herman, Ph.D., 1921 May-1974 May, 1975 June 1-1978 May 31 (Box 4A, Folder 13)
    - Stark, Nathan - Tech. Bd., 1975 June 1-1978 May 31 (Box 4A, Folder 14)
    - Wells, Herman B. - Tech. Bd., 1973 June 1-1978 May 31 (Box 4A, Folder 15)
    - Zimmer, James G., M.D. - Consultant, 1972 (Box 4A, Folder 16)
  - Ex-Employees' Personal Files
    Employee records are restricted for seventy-five years after the employee's termination date.
    - Axworthy, Mrs. Leona Constance, 1964 March 2-June 11 (Box 4B, Folder 1)
    - Badgley, Robin F., 1963 (Box 4B, Folder 2)
    - Baker, Marilyn, 1961-1963 (Box 4B, Folder 3)
    - Bloom, Samuel W., Ph.D., 1966 May 1-1971 April 30 (Box 4B, Folder 4)
    - Brown, Mary Allison - August 1, 1968 -, 1968 August 1-1969 February (Box 4B, Folder 5)
    - Brown, Howard J., M.D., 1966 October 13-1968 May (Box 4B, Folder 6)
    - Calhoun, Suzanne, 1966 May 16-1967 Mat 19 (Box 4B, Folder 7)
    - Chudiak, Barbara T., 1964 September 21-1967 September 22 (Box 4B, Folder 8)
    - Clark, Dean A., M.D. - Consultant, 1956 March 21-1963 April 30 (Box 4B, Folder 9)
    - Cooke, Robert B., Jr., 1965 March 22-31 (Box 4B, Folder 10)
    - Deutschman, Zygmunt, 1968-1971 (Box 4B, Folder 11)
    - Elinson, Jack, Ph.D., 1966 October 13-1970 April 30 (Box 4B, Folder 12)
    - Evans, Barbara, 1963 September 16-1966 May 31 (Box 4B, Folder 13)
    - Falk, Isidore, 1933-1945 (Box 4B, Folder 14)
    - Fischer, Ellen P., 1967 May 11-1969 September 30 (Box 4B, Folder 15)
    - Frank, Myrna E., 1962 August 16-1967 (Box 4B, Folder 16)
    - Giron, Arturo, 1964 (Box 4B, Folder 17)
    - Gould, Joanna R., 1968 August 5-1970 (Box 4B, Folder 18)
    - Green, Matthew, 1969 February 14-October 31 (Box 4B, Folder 19)
    - Grossman, Janet L., 1967 October 16-November 30 (Box 4B, Folder 20)
    - Huxley, Matthew, 1957 March 14-1963, 1983 (Box 4B, Folder 21)
    - Hyde, Henry van Zile, M.D., 1963 May 1-1967 April (Box 4B, Folder 22)
    - Ingelson, Liz, 1960 (Box 4B, Folder 23)
    - Jacobson, Edith, 1958-1961 (Box 4B, Folder 24)
    - Janelly, Dora, 1976 (Box 4B, Folder 24)
    - Leighton, Alexander H., M.D. - Consultant, 1956 October 15-1964 (Box 4B, Folder 25)
    - MacLeod, Colin M., M.D., 1963 May 1-1966 (Box 4B, Folder 26)
    - MacLeod, J. Wendell, M.D., O.B.E., 1963 May 1-1971 April 30 (Box 4B, Folder 27)
    - McKeever, Catherine E., 1963 September 3-1967 September 30 (Box 4B, Folder 28)
    - Martinez, Socorro, 1969 January 1-August (Box 4B, Folder 29)
    - Nelson, Iris, 1964 August 17-28 (Box 4B, Folder 30)
    - O'Brien, Theresa, 1957 July-1960 August (Box 4B, Folder 31)
    - O'Mullen, Eileen, 1961 April 17-1979 (Box 4B, Folder 32)
    - Ortega, Dolores Nina, 1963 (Box 4B, Folder 33)
    - Pascal, Mirtha, 1964 February 10-1967 June 9 (Box 4B, Folder 34)
    - Reed, Lowell J., Ph.D., Consultant, 1957 January 1-1966 (Box 4B, Folder 35)
    - Richardson, George Raymond John, 1966 July 8-November 4 (Box 4B, Folder 36)
    - Rubal, Louis, 1942 July 13-1962 December 10 (Box 4C, Folder 1)
    - Russak, Debbie I., 1968 February 15-August 15 (Box 4C, Folder 2)
    - Schulman, Paul, 1968 April 8-1969 January 15 (Box 4C, Folder 3)
    - Schulte, Marjorie, 1964 October 26-1967 July 28 (Box 4C, Folder 4)
    - Sharp, Mrs. Anamaria, 1967 September 4-December 20 (Box 4C, Folder 5)
    - Shultes, Enid M., 1925 November 30-1961 April 20 (Box 4C, Folder 6)
    - Small, Vivian, 1958-1966 (Box 4C, Folder 7)
    - Sobrino, Angela R., 1966 (Box 4C, Folder 8)
    - Stewart, William H., M.D., 1965 October 14-1969 (Box 4C, Folder 9)
    - Tompkins, Elizabeth C. (Mrs. Willie)Waldron, Mrs., 1964 January 2-1965 October (Box 4C, Folder 10)
    - Waldron, Mrs. Sally C., 1967 October 16-1968 June (Box 4C, Folder 11)
    - Ware, Willie Joseph, 1969 January 1-February 9 (Box 4C, Folder 12)
    - Westoff, Charles, 1952 September-1955 August (Box 4C, Folder 13)
    - Winslow, C.-E. A., 1951-1957 (Box 4C, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous Files
    - Milbank, Albert G. (Box 5)
    - Milbank, Tweed, Hadley & McCloy - 1957 - 1966 (Box 5)
    - Baehr, George, M.D. - 1968 - (Box 5)
    - Picture and Biography of Alexander Robertson, M.D. (Box 5)
    - Photographs of Dr. Robertson (Box 5)
    - Robertson, Alexander (Box 5)
    - Robertson, Alexander - 1970 - (Box 5)
    - Milbank, Samuel R. - 1957 - 1966 (Box 5)
    - Milbank, Samuel R. (Box 5)
    - Lawrence Kimball Altman, M.D. (Box 5)
    - Sheps, Cecil G., M.D. - 1964 - 1975 (Box 5)
    - Brauntuch, Jack, The J.M. Foundation - 1983 (Box 5)
    - Forger, Alexander D. - 1976 - (Box 5)
    - Correspondence with Musselman, Francis H. - 1962 - (Box 5)
    - Parkinson, Thomas I. - 1962 - (Box 5)
    - Read, Professor Margaret Helen - 1968 - 1969 (Box 5)
    - Read, Margaret - 1967 (Box 5)
    - Read, Margaret - Special Consultant - 1963 - 1966 (Box 5)
    - Robertson, Alexander, M.D. - March 1962, 1970 (Box 5)
    - Robertson, Alexander, M.D. - June 1962, 1968 (Box 5)
    - Security Against Sickness - I.S. Falk (Box 5)
    - Expenditures for Grants, Fellowships, Projects and Fund Activities 1905-1967 (Box 5)
    - Publication Contracts with Commercial Houses - 1931 (Box 5)
    - Finances 1934 (Box 5)
    - Finances 1934 (Box 5)
    - Index - Verbatim Record of Meetings of the Board of Directors, 1923 - 1927 (Box 6)
    - Verbatim Record of Meetings of the Board of Directors, 1928 - 1930 (Box 6)
    - Verbatim Record of Meetings of the Board of Directors, 1931 - 1935 (Box 6)
    - Grants, Fellowships, Projects and Fund Activities - 1905 - 1967; Bequests to Charities Under Will of Elizabeth Milbank Anderson (Box 6)
    - Appendix to Appraisal of Activities of the MMF - for the Five Year Period 1930 - 1934 (Box 6)
    - Milbank Memorial Fund Inventory and Appraisal as of February 20, 1964 by Consolidated Appraisal Co., Inc., NY (Box 6)
    - Minute in Memory of Elizabeth Milbank Anderson; Certificate of Incorporation; Fund Activities 1905 - 1937 (Box 6)
    - Minute in Memory of Elizabeth Milbank Anderson; Certificate of Incorporation; Fund Activities 1905 - 1962 (Box 6)
    - MMF General Ledger - 1958 - 1972 (Box 7)
- Additional material, 1920-1990; Accession 1993-M-007; 5.5 linear feet (5 boxes)
  Addition inventory by Diane E. Kaplan 1992 Jul
  Received from: Milbank Memorial Fund, 1992 July 22
  Includes Accession 1993-M-001 (see box 1, folder 1).
  Box 5 in Accession 1993-M-007 contains employee records which are restricted for seventy-five years after the employee's termination date. Expiration dates of restrictions are indicated at the folder level.
  - Demonstrations in rural public health administration, Cattaraugus County and Syracuse, New York: photographs, Circa 1930s (Box 1)
    From Accession 1993-M-001
    See Also: OVERSIZE
  - Milbank Quarterly
    - Front and back matter, miscellaneous correspondence, etc. dealing with preparation
      - Volume 55, No. 1 - Volume 66, No. 4 (plus supplements 1 and 2), 1977-1988 (Box 1)
      - Volume 67, No. 1 - Volume 68, No. 4 (plus supplements), 1989-1990 (Box 2)
      - Volume 68, AIDS supplements 1 and 2, 1990 (Box 2)
    - Requests to reprint articles, 1970-1977 (Box 2)
    - Requests to reprint articles, 1978-1988 (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous requests and inquiries files ( Milbank Memorial Fund Quarterly/Health and Society ), 1977-1987 (Box 3)
    - Author index of publications of the Milbank Memorial Fund, undated (Box 3)
    - Editorial Board: agenda and minutes, 1967-1971 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous files
    - Milbank Memorial Fund - Initial Report since 1905, 1921 May 11 (Box 3)
    - Memorandum for Board of Directors concerning Milbank Memorial Fund Operations, 1932 (Box 3)